<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>The Kings most excellent Maiestie, finding that the infection of the plague is at this present in sundry places of the city of London, ...</title>
            <author>England and Wales. Sovereign (1603-1625 : James I)</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <editionStmt>
            <edition>
               <date>1606</date>
            </edition>
         </editionStmt>
         <extent>Approx. 6 KB of XML-encoded text transcribed from 1 1-bit group-IV TIFF page image.</extent>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>Text Creation Partnership,</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Ann Arbor, MI ; Oxford (UK) :</pubPlace>
            <date when="2014-11">2014-11 (EEBO-TCP Phase 2).</date>
            <idno type="DLPS">B12743</idno>
            <idno type="STC">STC 8396</idno>
            <idno type="STC">Interim Tract Supplement Guide 506.h.10[68]</idno>
            <idno type="EEBO-CITATION">99892784</idno>
            <idno type="PROQUEST">ocm99892784</idno>
            <idno type="VID">187164</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>To the extent possible under law, the Text Creation Partnership has waived all copyright and related or neighboring rights to this keyboarded and encoded edition of the work described above, according to the terms of the CC0 1.0 Public Domain Dedication (http://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/). This waiver does not extend to any page images or other supplementary files associated with this work, which may be protected by copyright or other license restrictions. Please go to https://www.textcreationpartnership.org/ for more information about the project.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <seriesStmt>
            <title>Early English books online text creation partnership.</title>
         </seriesStmt>
         <notesStmt>
            <note>(EEBO-TCP ; phase 2, no. B12743)</note>
            <note>Transcribed from: (Early English Books Online ; image set 187164)</note>
            <note>Images scanned from microfilm: (Early English books; Tract supplement ; C7:1[68])</note>
         </notesStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <biblFull>
               <titleStmt>
                  <title>The Kings most excellent Maiestie, finding that the infection of the plague is at this present in sundry places of the city of London, ...</title>
                  <author>England and Wales. Sovereign (1603-1625 : James I)</author>
                  <author>James I, King of England, 1566-1625.</author>
               </titleStmt>
               <extent>1 sheet ([1] p.).   </extent>
               <publicationStmt>
                  <publisher>By Robert Barker, printer to the Kings most excellent Maiestie.,</publisher>
                  <pubPlace>Imprinted at London :</pubPlace>
                  <date>Anno 1606.</date>
               </publicationStmt>
               <notesStmt>
                  <note>Title from opening lines of text.</note>
                  <note>Dated at end: Hampton Court, the three and twentieth day of September, in the fourth yeere of our reigne ... .</note>
                  <note>Adjourning part of Michaelmas term because of plague; continuing collection of money due to the King. Cf. STC.</note>
                  <note>Reproduction of original in the British Library.</note>
               </notesStmt>
            </biblFull>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <projectDesc>
            <p>Created by converting TCP files to TEI P5 using tcp2tei.xsl,
      TEI @ Oxford.
      </p>
         </projectDesc>
         <editorialDecl>
            <p>EEBO-TCP is a partnership between the Universities of Michigan and Oxford and the publisher ProQuest to create accurately transcribed and encoded texts based on the image sets published by ProQuest via their Early English Books Online (EEBO) database (http://eebo.chadwyck.com). The general aim of EEBO-TCP is to encode one copy (usually the first edition) of every monographic English-language title published between 1473 and 1700 available in EEBO.</p>
            <p>EEBO-TCP aimed to produce large quantities of textual data within the usual project restraints of time and funding, and therefore chose to create diplomatic transcriptions (as opposed to critical editions) with light-touch, mainly structural encoding based on the Text Encoding Initiative (http://www.tei-c.org).</p>
            <p>The EEBO-TCP project was divided into two phases. The 25,368 texts created during Phase 1 of the project (2000-2009), initially available only to institutions that contributed to their creation, were released into the public domain on 1 January 2015. The approximately 40,000 texts produced during Phase 2 (2009- ), of which 34,963 had been released as of 2020, originally similarly restricted, were similarly freed from all restrictions on 1 August 2020. As of that date anyone is free to take and use these texts for any purpose (modify them, annotate them, distribute them, etc.). But we do respectfully request that due credit and attribution be given to their original source.</p>
            <p>Users should be aware of the process of creating the TCP texts, and therefore of any assumptions that can be made about the data.</p>
            <p>Text selection was based on the New Cambridge Bibliography of English Literature (NCBEL). If an author (or for an anonymous work, the title) appears in NCBEL, then their works are eligible for inclusion. Selection was intended to range over a wide variety of subject areas, to reflect the true nature of the print record of the period. In general, first editions of a works in English were prioritized, although there are a number of works in other languages, notably Latin and Welsh, included and sometimes a second or later edition of a work was chosen if there was a compelling reason to do so.</p>
            <p>Image sets were sent to external keying companies for transcription and basic encoding. Quality assurance was then carried out by editorial teams in Oxford and Michigan. 5% (or 5 pages, whichever is the greater) of each text was proofread for accuracy and those which did not meet QA standards were returned to the keyers to be redone. After proofreading, the encoding was enhanced and/or corrected and characters marked as illegible were corrected where possible up to a limit of 100 instances per text. Any remaining illegibles were encoded as &lt;gap&gt;s. Understanding these processes should make clear that, while the overall quality of TCP data is very good, some errors will remain and some readable characters will be marked as illegible. Users should bear in mind that in all likelihood such instances will never have been looked at by a TCP editor.</p>
            <p>The texts were encoded and linked to page images in accordance with level 4 of the TEI in Libraries guidelines.</p>
            <p>Copies of the texts have been issued variously as SGML (TCP schema; ASCII text with mnemonic sdata character entities); displayable XML (TCP schema; characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or text strings within braces); or lossless XML (TEI P5, characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or TEI g elements).</p>
            <p>Keying and markup guidelines are available at the <ref target="http://www.textcreationpartnership.org/docs/.">Text Creation Partnership web site</ref>.</p>
         </editorialDecl>
         <listPrefixDef>
            <prefixDef ident="tcp"
                       matchPattern="([0-9\-]+):([0-9IVX]+)"
                       replacementPattern="http://eebo.chadwyck.com/downloadtiff?vid=$1&amp;page=$2"/>
            <prefixDef ident="char"
                       matchPattern="(.+)"
                       replacementPattern="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/textcreationpartnership/Texts/master/tcpchars.xml#$1"/>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="eng">eng</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="http://authorities.loc.gov/">
               <term>Plague --  England --  Law and legislation --  Early works to 1800.</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2014-01</date>
            <label>TCP</label>Assigned for keying and markup</change>
         <change>
            <date>2014-01</date>
            <label>SPi Global</label>Keyed and coded from ProQuest page images</change>
         <change>
            <date>2014-02</date>
            <label>Anne Simpson</label>Sampled and proofread</change>
         <change>
            <date>2014-02</date>
            <label>Anne Simpson</label>Text and markup reviewed and edited</change>
         <change>
            <date>2014-03</date>
            <label>pfs</label>Batch review (QC) and XML conversion</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text xml:lang="eng">
      <body>
         <div type="proclamation">
            <pb facs="tcp:187164:1" rendition="simple:additions"/>
            <head>
               <g ref="char:leaf">❧</g> By the King.</head>
            <p>
               <hi>
                  <seg rend="decorInit">T</seg>He Kings moſt Excellent Maieſtie, finding that the infection of the</hi> Plague is at this preſent in ſundry places of the City of London, &amp; neere adioyning to the ſame, though not (God be thanked) with the mortalitie of great numbers; yet ſo diſperſed in diuers of the beſt and moſt open ſtreets of the ſaid Citie, as doe giue iuſt cauſe to doubt, that the contagion thereof, by great reſort of people, might be further ſpread, aſwell in the City, as into other parts of the Realme, whereby both danger might enſue to his Royal perſon, the Queene his deareſt wife, and his children, and to his moſt louing Subiects repayring thither for their Suites and cauſes, and likewiſe by ſuch increaſe of the infection, if it ſhould happen (which God forbid) the next Seſſion of his High<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>neſſe Parliament, appointed for the great and waighty affaires of the Realme, might bee prorogued: His Maieſtie, for theſe neceſſary conſiderations, and hoping that the infection will, by the goodneſſe of Almighty God, with the coldneſſe of the yeere, and ſuch wholeſome Orders as are taken in his ſaid Citie, the rather ceaſe by the adiournement of part of this next Terme of S. Michael now at hand, from the <hi>Vtas</hi> of the ſame, vntil the fourth Returne of the ſaid Terme called <hi>Menſe Michaelis</hi> next comming. His Maieſtie therefore, of his eſpeciall fauour and clemencie, is pleaſed and contented, to ad<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>iourne the ſaid Terme of S. Michael, that is to ſay, From the <hi>Vtas</hi> thereof, vnto the ſaid fourth Returne of the ſaid Terme, called <hi>Menſe Michaelis</hi> next comming; Which his Maieſtie ſignifieth to all and ſingular his louing Subiects of this his Realme, to the intent that they and euery of them, which hath cauſe or commandement to appeare in any of his Highneſſe Courts at Weſtminſter, in or at any day or time from and after the ſaid <hi>Vtas</hi> of S. Michael, may tary at their dwellings, or where their buſineſſe otherwiſe ſhall lye, without reſorting to any of the ſayd Courts for that cauſe, before the ſaid <hi>Menſe Michaelis</hi> next comming, and that without danger of forfeiture, penaltie, or contempt to incurre towards his Highneſſe in that behalfe. And neuertheleſſe his Maieſties pleaſure is, That two of his Iuſtices, that is to ſay, of either Bench one, ſhall the firſt day of Michaelmas Terme, called <hi>Octabis Michaelis,</hi> according to the ancient order of the Lawes, keepe the Eſſoignes of the ſaid <hi>Octabis Michaelis.</hi> At which <hi>Vtas</hi> of S. Michael, Writs of adiournement ſhall be directed to the ſaid Iuſtices, giuing them authoritie to adiourne the ſaid Terme of S. Michael, that is to ſay, From the <hi>Vtas</hi> thereof, vntill the fourth Returne, as before is ſaid. And the ſaid adiournement ſhall be made in the firſt day of the ſaid <hi>Vtas,</hi> commonly called, the day of Eſſoignes. And further his Maieſties pleaſure is, That all matters, cauſes and Suits, depending in any of his other Courts betweene party and party, as in his Highneſſe Courts of Chancery, Starchamber, and Exchequer, Courts of Wards and Liueries, Duchy of Lancaſter, and Court of Requeſts, ſhall haue continuance, and the parties ſhall haue day from the date of theſe preſents, vntill the ſaid fourth Returne, as before is ſayd.</p>
            <p>Prouided alway, and his Maieſties pleaſure and commandement is, That all Collectors, Receiuors, Sheriffes, and other Accomptants, and all other perſons, that ſhould or ought to Accompt or pay any ſumme or ſummes of Money in any of his Maieſties Courts of Exchequer, Court of Wardes and Liueries, and of his Duchie of Lancaſter, or in any of them, or to enter into any Accompt in any of the ſayd Courts, ſhall repayre vnto the accuſtomed places at Weſtminſter, where his Highneſſe hath appointed ſuch Officers and Miniſters, as for that purpoſe his Maieſty hath thought expedient, and there to pay and doe in euery behalfe, as though no ſuch Proclamation of Adiournment had been had or made. And his High<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>neſſe further pleaſure and commandement is, That all Sheriffes ſhall returne their Writs and Proces againſt all ſuch Accomptants and Debtors, at the dayes therein appoynted. And if any perſon or perſons, who ought to accompt or pay any ſumme or ſummes of Money to his Maieſtie in any of the Courts and places aforeſayde, doe make default therein, That then his Highneſſe Writs and Proces ſhall be awarded and ſent forth againſt euery ſuch perſon and perſons, and the ſame to be duely and orderly ſerued, and returned by the Sheriffes and Officers thereunto appointed, in ſuch like maner and forme, as the ſame ſhould haue been, if this preſent Proclamation had not beene made. And if any Sheriffe or other Officer ſhall make default, or be negligent in ſeruing, executing, or returning of any the Writs and Proces aforeſaid, That then euery ſuch Sheriffe and other Officer, ſhall incurre ſuch paines and penalties, as by the ſayd Courts, or any of them ſhall be taxed and aſſeſſed; Willing and commaunding all and euery his Maieſties Sheriffes, Officers, Miniſters and Subiects, to whom it doeth or ſhall apperteine, to obſerue and keepe their aſſemblies and apparances with all their Re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>turnes and Certificates, in his Highneſſe ſayd Courts at Weſtminſter in <hi>Menſe Michaelis</hi> next comming, then and there to bee holden and kept, and there to doe their Offices and dueties in euery behalfe, in like maner and forme, as they ſhould or ought to haue done, if this preſent Proclamation had not beene had or made, as they will anſwere to the contrary at their perils. Giuen at our Honour of Hampton Court, the Three and twentieth day of September, in the Fourth yeere of our Reigne of great Britaine, France, and Ireland.</p>
            <closer>God ſaue the King.</closer>
         </div>
      </body>
      <back>
         <div type="colophon">
            <p>¶ Imprinted at London by Robert Barker, Printer to the Kings moſt Excellent Maieſtie. ANNO 1606.</p>
         </div>
      </back>
   </text>
</TEI>
